## Matthew Cullen

Rochester, New York, 14526 | 585-831-0531 | m23.cullen@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Linkedin</u> | <u>Personal Website</u>

#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Experienced software designer with quality assurance and supervisory experience. Possesses strong leadership and team-building skills. Serves as a team leader to manage problem solving issues on a weekly basis. Quick learner, collaborative and creative. Works well under pressure and adapts to new concepts. Strives to write simple efficient code and contribute to the developer community.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby | Rails | SQL | Javascript | React | Django | Redux | Python | HTML | css | Bootstrap

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Pet-Assistant Frontend Backend | Demo

Keep track of important dates and notes for all your pets

- Used React as the frontend framework to create a single page application
- Used Redux to handle state between multiple components
- Used css and javascript to create a responsive navigation bar and layout

#### Fortune Teller api/client Frontend Backend | Demo

Ask a question and let the cards answer for you with multiple tarot spread options

- Created a rails api backend with Postgresql to handle CRUD/DataBase
- Created a javascript front end to connect to the api
- Used bootstrap to create a simple UI design

#### Book Review App Ruby on Rails - Github | Demo

Signup or login with google to read, write and comment on book reviews.

- Used rails for CRUD actions and to connect to a sqlite3 database
- Created a login system that allows new users to sign up with the site or login with a google account.
- Used embedded Ruby to render views with data from the controllers

## Virtual Bookcase with Sinatra - Github | Demo

Organize and keep track of your books with this virtual bookcase

- Used Ruby with the Sinatra framework and object oriented programming
- Created a login system
- Implemented proper MVC structure

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Sandwich Maker, Bruegger's Bagels, Webster, New York

06/ 2019 - Present

Make an assortment of food to the customers and bruegger's standards

Engage customers in a friendly manner to meet all their needs

# Quality assurance/supervisor, Harbec, Ontario, New York

06/2011 - 02/2015

Worked as a team to communicate problems and ensure the correct changes were made.

Supervised a team of machine operators and parts runners

Used measurement tools to determine the quality of various parts.

## Groundskeeper, St. Ann's, Rochester, New York

07/ 2008 - 06/201

Responsible for the care and maintenance of the grounds and equipment

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School 09/ 2019 - 03/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program